BRIAN WATAI NAMBALE

Tel: +254-795908082

Email:wataibrian@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an inspiring, talented, ambitious and hardworking individual of integrity in my area of expertise and lead by example through collective responsibility and teamwork. Furthermore, I am adept at handling multiple tasks on a daily basis competently and working well under pressure.

A key strength is communication; building strong relationships with people in order to deliver the best results. I enjoy working in a challenging environment that can provide me with major knowledge and skills required for my own career benefit and company goals achievement.

CARRER OBJECTIVES

To be a young, self-driven achiever in my field of work and study willing to work beyond expectations to assist in the achievement of common goals. To work in a challenging environment that drives my urge to perform efficiently and that gives me a chance to embrace and learn from other people's achievements. To grow in my education field and gain skills to match the dynamic nature of my profession.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Aug 2016 – July 2022 : Kenyatta University

BSc. Biomedical Engineering

Second Class Honors (Upper division)

Jan 2012 – Nov 2015 : Murang'a High School

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

A-

Jan 2003 – Nov 2011 : Muting'ong'o Primary School

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

B+

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2022- Present:

Operations Manager at Royal Beauty Hub

- Oversee daily operations of the nail spa and salon
- Hire and train beauticians, as needed
- Organize employees' shifts, considering peak times and seasonality
- Order beauty products, like creams and essential oils and replenish stock
- Arrange for regular maintenance services for all equipment

- Apply hygiene practices across all beauty stations
- Ensure all beauty treatments meet high quality standards
- Maintain staff records, including salaries and working schedules
- Promote services, products and discounts on social media
- Receive payments from clients and track all transactions
- Keep updated records of costs and revenues (e.g., daily, monthly and quarterly).

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021: Biomed at Ministry of health Division of National Public Health Laboratory

- Preventative maintenance on machines under the department's responsibility for example microscopes among others
- Producing job cards and stickers for all machines received for calibration
- Repair of breakdown machines
- Calibration of Laboratory equipment for example: pipettes, thermometers, refrigerator, water bath, centrifuge, autoclaves and shakers
- Ensuring all departments and services under the scope of engineering are well maintained, efficient and free from hazards Page 1 of 3
- Data entry of calibrated machines for certificates of calibration
- Replacement of fluorescent lamps

June 2019 - Sep 2019:

Biomed Intern at Kenyatta National Hospital

- Radiology: Daily check of X-ray machine, MRI, CT scan and programming session on mammogram
- Critical Care Unit: Repair and servicing of ventilators
- Renal: Daily checks and repair of dialysis machines
- Theatre: Calibration of anesthesia machine and heart lung machine operation
- Accidents and Emergency: Repair and maintenance of laboratory equipment
- Calibration: Calibration of refrigerators and weighing scales
- Wards: repair, maintenance and operation of patient monitors
- Clinics: Repair, maintenance and daily checks on dental units, eye clinic and ENT equipment.
- Inspected laboratory and manufacturing equipment and immediately sent non-working devices out for repair.

Sep 2018 - Nov 2018:

Biomed Attache' at Kenyatta University

- Analysis of resistors, diodes, capacitors and inductors; their applications in electric circuits, importance and maintenance.
- Handle projects using optoelectronic devices such as photo resistors, photo diodes, phototransistors; their applications and maintenance.
- Smoothing out of DC voltage ripples to obtain a continuous signal from a rectified signal using a bridge rectifier and thyristor applications.
- Simulation of the audio amplifier circuit using proteus software, breadboard implementation and the soldering process

- Trouble shooting
- Power transmission and motor operation.
- AC generators and brushless generator operation.
- Domestic installation; consumer unit design, one way switch, two way switching, intermittent switches, three phase connection, socket connection and three phase motor connection design.
- Handling digital instruments and integrated circuits.
- Industrial switching
- Motor starting
- Automation

SKILLS

• Metal works: brazing, soldering

• Design: solid works, AUTOCAD

• Database management: SQL, MySQL

• Programming: MATLAB, C++

Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Predictive learning using machine language
- Repair and maintenance of medical equipment
- Calibration of laboratory equipment

ACHIEVEMENTS

1. Qualified to participate in the 2019 Bootcamp on Covid 19 organized by UNECA. We worked in groups whereby our group was tasked with designing an enhanced medical device and personal protection gear. We fairly competed against other groups and emerged winners. Our project was titled "Covid Auxikit" and can be found online on the Ubora platform. https://platform.ubora-biomedical.org/projects/8b85316e-82f5-4017-8dbb-f6d99bc72da9

Covid Auxikit is a personal protective equipment package that contains:

- i. Filtered masks apt for sterilization
- ii. Re-usable face shield
- iii. Portable UV light sterilizer
- 2. Qualified to become a Hult Prize Foundation on Campus ambassador tasked with leading the execution of the Hult Prize program on university campus, with the goal of training, educating and inspiring students.
- 3. While serving as the university ambassador, I was nominated by the Hult Prize Foundation in collaboration with the World Food Program to compete in the Hult Prize 2021 challenge: Food for Good with an aim to impact over 10,000,000 people by 2030 through tackling the 7 sustainable development goals. My colleagues and I worked on a project called

Chakula Connect whose aim was to connect the consumers to food and help producers to generate quality affordable food products through offering training, advice and linking them with the market. We managed to emerge as semi-finalists in the tight competition.

4. Nominated to become Kenyatta University ambassador tasked with the organization and coordination of the Kenyatta University Career Week 2020.

INTERESTS

- Research and innovation
- Programming
- Traveling
- Performing analyses
- Database designing
- Web development

REFEREES

Please feel free to contact the under mentioned in regard to my competence, work ethic, performance and / or any other aspect with respect to me:

Eng. Calvin Simba	Eng. Mboka	Dr. June Madete
Biomed	Head of Department	The Chairperson
National Public Health Laboratory	Kenyatta National Hospital	Electrical and Electronic
Tel: 0722 291 862	Tel: 0725720378	Engineering Department
Calvsimba1@gmail.com	dmboka2010@gmail.com	Kenyatta University
		Tel: 0723525361
		Madete.june@ku.ac.ke